早晨。
作為立法會主席。
改善民生。
有助經濟發展。
理解同埋支持。
全國人大因應最新嘅。
我對此係表示尊重。
行使憲法賦予嘅職能。
形勢同埋實際嘅情況。
其中一項議程就係人大常委。
嘅決定草案嘅建議。
國家同埋香港嘅穩定。
誒，全國人民代表大會今日開幕。
國家安全係全國人民安居樂業嘅基礎。
制定相關嘅法律制度係符合國家以至香港社會整體嘅利益。
提請審議全國人民代表大會關於建立健全香港特別行政區維護國家安全嘅法律制度同埋執行機制。
哦。
根據基本法。
to safeguard national security.
香港有憲制責任。
就《基本法》第二十三條立法。
因like of the latest development and actual situation。
will facilitate the economic development and improvement of people's livelihood.
The annual session of the National People's Congress commences today.
國家安全是的 bedrock， underpinning the well-being of people.
香港特別行政區係中華人民共和國不可分離嘅部分。
this is in line with the interests of the country and Hong Kong society as a whole.
我認為特區政府喺適當時候應該展開相關嘅工作。
成功落實一國兩制係確保香港嘅繁榮穩定，亦都係我哋香港市民嘅共同願望。
Republic of China, safeguarding stability of the whole country and Hong Kong as its special administrative region.
The NPC exercise its power enshrined in the Constitution of PRC to establish the relevant legal system.
One of the agenda items is to deliberate the resolution put forward by NPC Standing Committee on establishing and improving the legal system and enforcement mechanisms for the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.
講咧。
未能。
我哋都。
understand and support this initiative.
其實你你係喺咩基礎底下去？
喺誒基本法二十三條納到法。
This is also the wish shared by Hong Kong people.
作為主席長，我尊重。
The government should commence the relevant work at the appropriate time.
The Hong Kong SAR is an an inalienable part of PLC.
人大常委、人大去進行呢一樣嘢係可以理解嘅。
我諗即係睇個事實上咧，就係個實際情況係經過二十三年。
唔使自己去處理呢件即係咁具爭議性嘅事情，就係咪鬆一口氣咧？另外，想問下，頭先你指出咧，即係國家安全立法，香港想即係想要嘅嘢啊。
香港 has the constitutional responsibilities to enact laws in accordance with Article Twenty Three of Basic Law.
The successful implementation of one country, two systems can ensure the prosperity and stability of Hong Kong.
亦都係過去嗰幾年，大家睇個情況咧，香港嘅情況咧係出咗好大嘅變化，尤其是舊年。噉我覺得即係基於實際情況，誒。
可以。
公司嘅。
再睇。
我。
最近。
唔該。
Greater Alpha。
and also the end of Hong Kong.
using their constitutional power.
simple answer. The second thing is that NPC is
and also looking at the real situation in Hong Kong, and I think they cannot tolerate any more, and therefore they have to put a resolution to.
誒包括二十三條誒，或者即係下個禮拜嘅國歌法都要處理。噉我都希望大家咧都係冷靜去睇依件事，去大家去處理咧，都係為香港整體誒市民嘅利益。
我諗誒，大家係咪想喺過去嗰誒一年裏邊，每日有好多誒疏亂啊，有好多冇正常生活去過咧？咁呢個係咪誒香港人所願咧？噉我覺得即係大家都可以睇得到嘅。啊，係咪繞個誒？
誒，我頭先講咗呢一個係人大誒，佢嘅喺誒中國憲法裏邊，佢有責任去維護國家安全。你話係咪啊？好似誒鬆一啖口氣咧？我諗作為立法會主席咧，任何法例攞到嚟咧，我嚟處理嘅。
I think to answer your second question first. This morning, Premier also reiterated that you know one country two systems is the central policy of the central government. So this is definitely not the end.
Of one country two system, I think we need to work hard to maintain that one country two system do work for Hong Kong, and I believe that Hong Kong people also want one country two system to succeed, and so is the central government. So I think that's the.
最。
好快都變。
OK，好，唔該曬。
If we continue like this in Hong Kong,
loophole to plug the loophole，okay。
enact the legal system to help Hong Kong and also to help the national security.
what about the livelihood of our people, of our economy, of our business? So I think there is something that under the real situation, NPC felt that they need to act.